mapleta.com 2017-08-07

# Our Position on Privacy and Data Protection - Maplesoft

_Last updated: Jan 22, 2010_

Waterloo Maple Inc. (“ **Maplesoft** ”, “ **We** ” or “ **us** ”) is concerned about protecting the personal information (personal information is defined as any information relating to an identified or identifiable individual) it gathers about the users, visitors and customers (collectively, “ **Users** ”, and individually a “ **User** ”) of our websites, including without limitation, www.maplesoft.com (the “ **Web Site** ”), our online store (the “ **Web Store** ”), other Maplesoft web pages, software, services and products (collectively, referred to as the “ **Services** ”).

We believe that individuals have the right to be informed about the information being collected about them and about its intended use. Individuals also have the right to review information being retained and the means to update and correct it.

To help you better understand how your personal information is protected at Maplesoft, we are providing you with the following statement (the “ **Privacy Statement** ”) describing our practices and policies with respect to the privacy of User information. In the event you terminate your relationship with us, or become an inactive customer, we will continue to adhere to the policies and practices described in this notice.

This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to the terms and conditions of Maplesoft’s terms of use, which are located at: <http://www.maplesoft.com/terms/>. 

**  
The Maplesoft Web Site**  
When you are visiting and/or using the Services, as applicable, we want you to feel secure that Maplesoft is respecting your privacy. The only private information we have about you is the information you choose to give us by filling out a form or an order.

The Services use "cookies" to record basic information entered on some forms and to record "shopping baskets" in the Web Store. A cookie is a piece of data that identifies you as a unique user. Maplesoft uses this information to better serve all visitors as we improve the content and design of the Services, and to enhance the convenience of using the Services by reducing redundant information entry for Users.

The default setting on most web browsers is to accept cookies. You can change this setting to refuse any cookie, or to be prompted when a cookie is being sent. Please note, however, that some areas and features of the Services will not function properly if you refuse cookies.

**Privacy Policy**  
Maplesoft recognizes that appropriate protection and management of personal information is critical and is responsible for personal information in its possession or custody. We have adopted the following privacy principles for the protection of the personal information of Users.

  1. Maplesoft will provide Users with easily understood information about its policies regarding the collection, use and disclosure of personal information.
  2. Maplesoft will limit the collection and use of personal information to that which is needed for valid business purposes, or to comply with applicable law, and any such data will be obtained only by lawful and fair means.
  3. Maplesoft will strive to maintain the accuracy of personal information, including establishing mechanisms allowing Users to have the opportunity to review and correct their personal information.
  4. Maplesoft will not disclose personal information to third parties, unless:
    * The User requests it; 
    * The data is provided to help complete a user-initiated transaction;
    * The disclosure is required by law;
    * The User has been informed about the possibility of such disclosure and has agreed to it;
    * The User has purchased a MapleConnect third party product. For these purchases, User contact information will be provided to the third party
product developer in order for them to fulfill their support and service obligations to the User; or 
    * Where the User is a resident of a jurisdiction other than Canada or the United States, Maplesoft may also disclose personal information to our authorized third party partner located in the jurisdiction where the User resides. Please visit <http://www.maplesoft.com/contact/international/> to view a list of our authorized third partners by jurisdiction. 
  5. Maplesoft uses contractual or other means to provide protection for the personally identifiable information that is disclosed third parties. 
  6. Maplesoft may share personal information gathered through the Services and amongst our corporate parents (including, without limitation, Cybernet Systems Co., LTD.), subsidiaries, affiliates or divisions for internal business purposes in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If Maplesoft shares your information within its corporate family, we will ensure that your information continues to be used only in accordance with this Privacy Policy and your expressed choices.

**Email Communications** **  
**  
Maplesoft operates multiple commercial subscription-based email lists that interested parties can opt-in or opt-out of at any time from the [email management area](http://www.maplesoft.com/subscribers/subscription_list.aspx) of the Maplesoft web site. If you are a member of Maplesoft.com, you can also manage your preferences from within the [Member Center](http://www.maplesoft.com/Members/member_center_main.aspx). 

From time to time, Maplesoft may create new subscription-based commercial email lists and may pre-populate these lists with existing Maplesoft email list subscribers, based on subscriber profiles. If you are not already a Maplesoft email subscriber, you will not be added to any newly created Maplesoft email lists. 

If you are a Maplesoft customer, and/or you have communicated with Maplesoft within the past 2 years, you may periodically receive emails from Maplesoft staff or from a Maplesoft email account ending with @maplesoft.com, including emails such as new product updates, security updates, technical updates, customer service updates, and other commercial email communications considered relevant to you, based on your customer or contact profile. 

If you would prefer to never receive commercial emails from Maplesoft, you have the option to remove yourself from all present and future email lists by globally unsubscribing [here ](http://www.maplesoft.com/subscribers/global_unsubscribe.aspx). You may still subscribe to any Maplesoft email list after globally unsubscribing, and by doing so you will be removed from the global unsubscribe list and put on the list(s) that you subscribe to.

Emails verifying opt-in and opt-out requests are automatically sent to the recipient after each email subscription update. 

**Safeguarding Security**  
Maplesoft will take appropriate steps to ensure that personal information is protected from unauthorized access and disclosure, including limited access to such data only to those employees with a business need to know. Maplesoft will apply these principles regardless of the specific technologies employed for data collection and use. 

**FERPA**  
Maplesoft has reviewed the requirements of the [Family Education Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA)](https://ed.gov/policy/gen/guid/fpco/ferpa/index.html), and we have identified nothing in any Maplesoft product or service that could prevent or impede a school from complying with the FERPA requirements.

**Contact Information**  
To ask questions or express concerns, please contact our Privacy Officer by email at [privacy@maplesoft.com](mailto:privacy@maplesoft.com), or by postal mail at: Maplesoftfs Privacy Officer, 615 Kumpf Drive, Waterloo, ON, Canada, N2V1K8. The Privacy Officer will investigate any complaints that concern our compliance with this privacy policy.
